When you put a bunch of regulators
together in a room, what do they come
out with? Hyperregulatory solutions.
>> What happens when three SEC regulators
walk into a bar?
>> Okay. Well, there's this talk about if
something is security or not. But why
does it matter to me? I think regulatory
framework can sort of serve as a barrier
to entry. It can fence in incumbent
firms and make it very hard for anyone
else to do anything because there's so
many prescriptive rules. You can buy a
pair of shoes that is in the line of an
athlete that you really like and you're
buying it not because the shoes are so
comfortable, because you think that
athlete is cool and that doesn't make
the shoe a security, right? You can
transfer value in the same way that you
transfer
information now. And that's been so
powerful to us, right? The internet has
done amazing things for us as a society
because you can so easily transfer
information. And the idea that now you
can do the same thing with value is
really potentially life-changing. This
is one of the things that's really
bothered me in the crypto space is
[Music]
>> changing tides in the administration
have meant new regulations for crypto
industries. Now, what is next for
regulations? We're here to talk about
this theme with our next guest, Hester
Pur. She is a commissioner of the US
Securities and Exchange Commission, uh,
unofficially and warmly dubbed Crypto
Mom. Thank you very much for joining the
program. I'm joined by
>> Bonnie Chang.
>> Commissioner Pur, it's great honor to
finally speak with you in person. I've
had you on the show recently and um,
looking forward to getting your thoughts
on the crypto task force and what's
next. I want to start with a story that
you told at your remarks at um SEC
speaks on May 19th. It was incredible.
Can you tell the story and why it
motivates you? Sure. Well, Bonnie,
David, thank you for having me. It's
great to be here. I've got to start with
my disclaimer, which is my views are my
own views as a commissioner, not
necessarily those of the SEC or my
fellow commissioners. Um, so I I told
the story of um an an old man named
Samuel Whitmore who was um a farmer at
the time of the American Revolution. And
so when the when the American Revolution
started, he actually got out there even
though he was 80 years old or just about
80 years old, he got out there and he uh
he got right into the fight and he um he
shot some British soldiers and then he
himself got bayonetted and stomped. They
were tried to kill him basically and
left him for dead and he he ended up
living another another 20 years after
that. And so we had in our family um
passed down was his teacup that he had
it it was missing its handle because he
had buried it in his backyard when the
Boston Tea Party happened and the tea
taxes were there and he said that he
would not um he would not stand for
that. He would not drink tea until that
issue was resolved. So what I what I
wanted to say in that speech is you know
it's it's right around Memorial Day
which is when we think about about our
American soldiers who have fought for us
and and other uh military folks who have
fought for us and for our freedom and
the idea is that there are a lot of
people who have really fought for the
freedom of this country and we want to
make sure that um we take advantage of
what they fought for which is the
freedom to speak the freedom to to think
for ourselves and I think that is a lot
of what's underlying the the the
movement around trying to decentralize
things, trying to figure out ways that
you can um interact directly with your
peers. Uh and so I think there's some of
that ethos that really is consistent
with what our country is built on. It's
>> incredible.
>> Well, you are the head of the new crypto
task force. Tell me about the genesis of
this task force and uh leading up to its
priorities right now. Yeah. So, we're
about four months in, right after the
inauguration that then acting chairman
Mark UEA set up the crypto task force
and put me in charge of it. Um, and it's
continued now that the new chairman Paul
Atkins has come in. And the idea is to
to take a look at the crypto policy at
the SEC and really try to figure out a
way forward that is very different than
what we were doing before. Before we
were using enforcement actions to set
policy and now what we're trying to do
is figure out first where our authority
lies, what sits within that authority,
tell people if things are outside that
authority, and then work on the things
that are within that authority, work on
making sure that those are regulated in
a way that recognizes the unique
characteristics of the technology and
and um also recognizes the objectives of
uh securities laws.
>> Is this crypto task force changing any
of the frameworks with which the SEC
makes decisions on certain you know just
certain tokens or cryptos for example
we've had a guest on yesterday who
criticized the howi test as being
outdated something used in the 30s for
bushels of wheat that are no longer
really applicable for tokenized assets
in today's digital economy. Well, I
think it's kind of funny that you
mentioned framework because I think one
of my criticisms has been that we really
haven't had a clear framework and that's
really what we're trying to develop
here. The Howie test is important
because we have a definition of security
that includes lots of different things
and one of those things is investment
contract
>> and that is how a lot of the um crypto
offerings have been analyzed using the
investment contract analysis that was
found in the Howy Supreme Court case.
So, is that case outdated? I mean, I
would argue that it actually can can
stand the test of time. It had to do
with, as everyone knows, Orange Groves
was was what was at issue in the Howy
case itself,
>> but since then, it's been used to cover
a lot of different types of assets that
are sold in connection with promises.
>> Um, and so crypto can function in that
same way. I think what's unusual is that
crypto assets themselves
have been trading on secondary markets
in a way that other objects of
investment contracts just typically
haven't done in the past. And that's
really posed some challenges for us as
we think about how the Howie framework
applies to um crypto assets. So I think
that's a challenge for us. It's a
challenge for Congress to think about. I
would argue that we could provide more
clarity around what an investment
contract is. And I think that would be
good not only for crypto but more
broadly so that people could understand
really what instances um are pulled into
the securities laws by by the investment
contract term. What are the differences
between security and um investment
contract?
>> So an investment contract is one subset
of a security. It's so you've got
stocks, bonds, and you also have
investment contracts. Um, and so it's
really designed to get at instances
where someone is saying, "Give me your
money, invested in this in this common
enterprise. We'll build something
together, and you we'll build something,
and you just sit back. You don't have to
do anything, and you will you will
benefit from the efforts of us, the
promoter, as we build something." And
so, it's really designed to capture that
kind of thing, which is a little bit
harder to pin down than something like a
share of stock. Um so investment of
money with the expectation of profits
based on the efforts of someone else. Um
you know how a lot of crypto projects
they promise you very early on um as an
angel investor that we're going to do
this together. So in this definition
that would be an investment contract but
then later on it becomes decentralized.
So there'll be a time when it's no
longer this contract. So Bonnie, I think
you're putting your finger on the on the
the big issue here, right? So what
happens when someone is trying to um get
a token out there into the world and get
lots of people buying it because that's
what generates the network effect. So So
what has happened um over time is we've
moved away from the from from the broad
retail offerings of these things. We've
started PE you've seen people start with
as you said it'll be venture capitalists
or other wealthy uh accredited investors
right and they'll get the initial token
or they'll get a a promise of getting
tokens later and then once the network
is more developed it it is sold more
broadly and the question becomes how
does the investment contract that
promise to build out the network that
was made to those initial venture
capital investors. Does that track along
with the token or is the token a
separate thing? And so I think that's
the that's the million-dollar question.
>> Have there been instances in which CS
the SEC and the CFTC have had
discussions over what constitutes either
a security and or a commodity and
whether or not something falls under the
jurisdiction of the SEC and the CFTC and
ultimately how have those discussions
been resolved? Yeah, I mean we talk all
the time with um with our our fellow
regulators at the CFTC and and across
the the government. Um so I mean these
are questions that we have to figure
out. I think you can have something that
starts out is is sold in a in a
transaction that we that we regulate
that ultimately and this depends too on
what Congress does that ultimately will
end up trading on platforms that the
CFTC regulates. But there's market
structure legislation as you know that's
being worked on. Um and so so that will
be worked out. But you know the CFTC and
the SEC have a lot of areas of common
>> jurisdiction or where our jurisdictions
bump up against each other because we're
unusual in the US and that we have two
separate regulators. And so it's very
common for us to have products that
people um or for there to be products
out there and people say, "Well, is it
CFTC regulated or is it SEC regulated?"
Those conversations are very common in
crypto and elsewhere.
I think a lot of people want to know,
okay, well, there's this talk about if
something is security or not, but why
does it matter to me?
Yeah, I mean that's a good question and
I think the reason that it matters is
because if if something is a security,
it triggers all kinds of other
obligations for anyone who touches and
interacts with it. So if you're a
trading platform and something is a
security, you have to register with us
as an exchange or there's an exchange
light the ATS that you can register as.
Um, and if you're if you're um helping
people, if you're a financial
professional helping people engage with
crypto, you need to know whether it's a
security because the rules are different
depending on whether it's a security. I
think though what we really want to
figure out is what protections does it
make sense to apply, right? Does it make
sense for the securities laws to apply?
And if if you are offering someone
something that is um a share of an
enterprise, right, we would think, okay,
the securities laws should apply because
that's what happens. Um you know, that's
that's what that framework is designed
for. And so trying to figure out does it
make sense for these things to be within
that framework and that really is a
facts and circumstances question. So we
are trying to build a framework that
enables people to know and not spend
hours and days and lots of money with
expensive lawyers trying to figure out
whether something is a security or not
but really to have clarity and then um
be able to move forward with building
the project.
>> Um similar line of questioning as
Bonnie. So on that note, some recent
statements you made regarding what is a
security and what isn't. So at the same
speech that Bonnie referenced earlier,
the SEC speaks event, you stated that
NFTs don't qualify a securities because
they don't reflect interest in a
business in a business. So is this a
recent change? And if so, how should NFT
creators now approach uh their projects?
>> Well, I'm glad you asked the question.
Again, it's a facts and circumstances
question, right? But what I was talking
about in that speech is if you have an
NFT that is designed so an artist
creates something and the NFT is
programmed so that it kicks royalties
back to that initial artist throughout
the the life of the NFT. That doesn't
pull it into uh the securities
framework. So you can have those kinds
of NFTs that are outside. You could
though tokenize a share of stock that
could be an NFT, right?
But that would obviously still be a
security. So it does matter what it is.
But I think what what I would have liked
the SEC to do many years ago was to put
out some guidance for NFT uh creators
because I think there was a lot of
interest in using NFTts to figure out
how to monetize people's creative
abilities. And I think that was slowed
by the fact that people were unsure
about what the security status was. we
brought some well-known cases um in this
area and and and so I think um people
there was a lot of uncertainty. So I do
want us to provide some clarity.
Obviously, a speech from one
commissioner is not the way to do that.
>> But I think what we're we're trying to
do is we're trying to start by laying
out some of these concepts. And
ultimately, you've seen that we've put
out some staff guidance on a number of
issues. And ultimately, where we hope to
get is to put things out in a way that's
more durable in a commission statement
um and and thinking about commission
rulemaking where that's appropriate as
well. And then obviously legislation
will be helpful to really make things um
more permanent.
>> Mhm. when you come up with a framework,
how do you balance um killing innovation
versus protecting investors?
>> Yeah, I mean the goal is obviously of
any regulatory framework is to um bring
a level of certainty and confidence to
investors so that they can engage in a
marketplace without worrying that um you
know they can't rely on what other
people are saying to them. So that's
kind of the purpose and within that
framework.
If investors are willing to invest, then
you're able to get capital flowing. And
I think that's why US capital markets
have been so successful is people have
been able to rely on the financial
statements that pe that companies put
out. They've been able to they they know
that if a company in raising money lies
to them, there is recourse. And so
that's healthy to have that environment.
But if you if you have an environment
that then um requires someone every time
she's trying to iterate um to get um uh
you know to to fit within a framework
that works for incumbents but doesn't
allow anything new then you don't get
any innovation. So a regulatory
framework can sort of serve as a barrier
to entry. It can fence in incumbent
firms and make it very hard for anyone
else to do anything because there's so
many prescriptive rules. And so I think
it's trying to have a principles-based
approach where you don't say um you have
to do things in this particular way, but
you say this is the objective that we
have. You can choose your way of
achieving that objective. And so I think
that's kind of the way to balance to
allow new things to come in. That's hard
for regulators. I mean, we've seen that
in areas other than crypto. Um
recordkeeping rules, something very
mundane. If we specify how records have
to be kept, well, that old technology
gets embedded into the rules. Meanwhile,
the firm is off using a much better
technology to keep records, but they've
got to have their one set of records for
recordkeeping um purposes for themselves
and then the other set is what they do
for the regulators using the old
technology. That doesn't make sense. And
so I think where we can to pull out the
technology specific requirements out of
rules that that can be helpful. And then
also just remembering the ethos, right?
This going back to your first question,
right? The American ethos is to say that
people have freedom to do things. And so
the presumption should be that people
have freedom to do things. and only
should there be a regulation stepping in
when it makes sense to overcome that
presumption because there's some
overriding pro investor protection
concern or market stability concern.
>> I believe in a recent speech and correct
me if I'm paraphrasing you incorrectly
uh Commissioner P, but you said that
technical participation in proof ofstake
systems do not fall under securities
guidelines. Is that correct? And what do
you mean by that? So I think there's
been a lot of uncertainty around whether
you can run a staking program um and
whether that somehow gets pulled into
the securities laws. And so it's
offering a technical service like uh
helping other people to stake in my view
does not constitute a securities
offering.
>> What exactly is technical participation
in this context?
So, I mean, people can stake themselves,
right? Individuals can stake their own
>> ETH, for example. Um, but often they'll
go to someone else to help them do do
that staking, right? They want technical
help in staking.
>> They want to be pulled with other maybe
they don't have enough to stake on their
own, so they want to be pulled with
other people to stake. Um so those kinds
of services that are offered I would
argue don't fit within
>> how does that change institutional
staking overall? Does that does that
open a lot of doors for a lot of this
kind of participation? I mean how do you
see this industry changing?
>> The goal in my view of providing clarity
in this area is to make sure that we're
not dissuading people from staking
because they worry that somehow they're
going to trip the securities laws.
>> Okay. So, I mean, you know, you can you
can craft almost anything to be a
securities offering.
>> So, it it does matter how you do it. Um,
but but I think that it it makes sense
for people to know that there are ways
to offer staking programs without that
tripping the securities laws and and and
that's an area where we can provide more
guidance. I think another one of those
areas we should have provided guidance
earlier. So, we put out a statement the
the staff of the division of corporation
finance at the SEC put out a statement
on mining. Um, and I think there's
similar issues in mining versus and
staking. So,
>> I think you did say most uh crypto asset
today are not securities. Um, what do
you mean by that?
>> So, when you think about what crypto
assets are out there, most of them are
not, you know, they're not tokenized
securities, right? They're not they're
they're just they're collectibles.
They're utility tokens of some sort. And
most of those just don't on their own
implicate the securities laws. Now
again, you can take anything. You can
take a chinchilla and you can sell it in
a way that that chinchilla becomes part
of a securities offering. You same with
a crypto asset. But I think when you
look at most of them, I mean, we're here
at the Bitcoin conference, right?
Bitcoin, you look at that not a
security. And so when I when I just look
across the landscape of assets, I come
to a very different conclusion than some
others at the SEC in the past have come
to. I really don't think most of these
are securities. Now that said, I think
as we open the doors for more engagement
on tokenization of traditional
securities, I think we're going to see a
real uptick in the number of crypto
assets that are securities because
you're tokenizing something like a bond
or like an equity and that is a is a
security. It was a security when it
wasn't tokenized and it will be when it
is tokenized. Can I use this example?
So, a lot of retail investors, they'll
look at Vitalik, for example, and be
like, "Oh, um, he's doing this thing.
Um, I think it looks good. I'm going to
buy some Ethereum." Or they look at
Anatoli and he comes up with this new
idea. I'm going to buy this token. Does
that mean there are some elements of
security in it? Well, I don't think that
you can say that that any product that
you buy because there is someone who's
highly involved with that product and
highly associated with that product that
that makes the product a security. Um,
you know, you can buy a pair of shoes
that is in the line of an athlete that
you really like and you're buying it not
because the shoes are so comfortable,
but because you think that athlete is
cool and that doesn't make the shoe a
security, right? And so I think we have
to we have to this is one of the things
that's really bothered me in the crypto
space is we've just taken
such a broad reading of the securities
laws to pull this stuff in in ways that
I don't think make sense. I do think
there are instances when the securities
laws make sense to apply and that's
where we should think about applying
them. But, you know, the fact that
you're buying a product because someone
that you admire or that you think is
smart is working on it doesn't
necessarily make it a security. Bitcoin
Asia 2025 is happening August 28th and
29th in Hong Kong and Eric Trump will be
there along with some of the biggest
names in Bitcoin. It's set to be the
biggest Bitcoin event in Asia this year.
And the best part, the general tickets
are free. Pro and whale passes are on
sale, but prices will go up soon. If
you're thinking about going, grab yours
now. Link is in the description.
>> Want to talk about some ETF offerings
now. So, the SEC recently postponed a
few ETF um offerings including Litecoin,
XRP
um and I think of last night Bitwise's
attempt to convert its crypto index into
an ETF. So, some of investors are
frustrated by this delay. Can you just
walk us through the decision-m process
here? Well, so I I did warn people at
the outset of this of this crypto task
force project that people would be
frustrated and this is definitely
manifesting itself this week. I've heard
a lot of complaints. Um and I I think
the point to remember is that there are
a lot of very we're a bureaucracy at the
SEC, right? there are a lot of rules
that have to be uh adhered to and their
processes and so we're working through
we've gotten a lot of applications on
the ETP side on the exchange traded
product side and so we're working
through those um but we have to do that
in a way that that will definitely
frustrate people
>> but just to be clear you're not ruling
out these listings right
>> no I think there there's we're not
ruling out the listings and even when
you see delays you shouldn't assume that
that's ruling it out. That's that's you
know there there are just technical
reasons for having to do
>> just to follow up on that. You've
previously criticized ETF management or
ETF listings about the SEC as being
>> terribly mismanaged. Can you just
elaborate on what you mean by that and
how you've planned to fix that
mismanagement?
>> Well, I think when you look at what
happened with the Bitcoin exchange
traded product that that saga, right, it
was a 10-year saga. And when I came into
the SEC in 2018,
we that was when we we we disapproved
the WLVOS ETP. Um and then it took us
until how many years later when did we
finalize that? You know, a number of
years later, right, many years later by
by the time we got to final. But what I
thought had happened in the interim was
it was just us looking for one excuse
after another to say no. And the target
kept moving of oh well you give us this
information now we want this
information. And I think people had
spent they were very frustrated because
they had spent a lot of money doing
analysis of why these fit within how we
had thought about other types of ETPs in
the past.
And so I really just think we should
have a regular order way of doing this.
People should know what the standards
are and that's where we want to get. And
that is so that is where we're trying to
get so that people have a clear idea of
what standards we're using to analyze
these things and then they can do the
analysis and they can present it to us.
Um and so that I think will be helpful.
It took a court to force our hand,
right? That was what ultimately led
those those to go out.
>> Um and so it shouldn't come to that. And
the the reason the court came in is
because they said you weren't following
procedure that made sense. And so we're
working on developing a procedure that
makes sense. But I will say, you know, a
lot of these come in and our staff has
to look at each one of them even for
things like did you, you know, is there
enough information here for us to make a
decision? And so that's a lot of work
for the staff and and I think that's
part of why things take a long time
because all of this is coming in. Um,
our staff is working on lots of other
things and so that that is why it's
taking a little while.
>> Yes.
>> Take me back to the moment when you
learn about crypto or were you kind of
forced to learn about crypto because of
all these laws or regulations?
>> No, I learned about crypto before I got
to the SEC. I learned about it from a
colleague at at a prior um job who was
very interested in crypto. And what what
I thought was was exciting about it is
this idea that you can transfer value in
the same way that you transfer that
you've been able to transfer information
now. And that's been so powerful to us,
right? The internet has done amazing
things for us as a society. There's
some, you know, negatives, too, but it's
done amazing things because you can so
easily transfer information. And the
idea that now you could do the same
thing with value is really a a a
potentially life-changing. Now maybe not
for as much for people in a society like
the United States, but there are other
places where having that ability to to
do that um is really life transforming.
So I think that was what first um
interested me about it. Um, I did not
anticipate having um so much of my work
consumed by thinking about how we can
set the rules for it, but I was
definitely uh taken by by that dramatic
change in in the way our society can
work. A lot of lawmakers are looking at
what you say. um for let's say a
lawmaker that doesn't know really know
what's going on or doesn't really know
how to proceed. What is your suggestion?
>> Well, I think the first thing is just as
you're looking at this issue, remember
basic American principles. So you know
freedom is really important for people
and this is a freedom enhancing
technology and so think about that
aspect of it and then I would say think
about applying what are you trying to
get at at the end of the day right if we
decide that we want a regulatory
framework for any or all of this think
about what the objectives are and try to
write your rules your your statutes in a
way that's as principled as possible so
that you're not micromanaging
the industry because if you micromanage
it, we don't know how it will develop.
Um, and if you micromanage it, it can't
develop in the way that it would
organically develop in response to what
people want and need. And so keep it as
focused on objectives instead of on on
micromanaging principles,
micromanaging uh like prescriptions, I
should say. My last question is while
developing this buring crypto task
force, are you looking at other count's
crypto regulations and frameworks as a
model? Um, anything or any one in
particular stand out to you?
>> Well, I think there are different
elements that we can take from different
places. I mean, the SEC has been very
slow to the game. So, we do have models
that we can look at, whether that's in
Japan or whether that's in Europe or the
UK.
um Singapore has been much more willing
to allow allow experimentation. There
are things that we can draw from that.
Um and I think we can also you know
going later has the advantage of seeing
what doesn't work. I am watching what's
happening in Europe with the different
implementation of of Mika across
different jurisdictions to see what what
works. Um and so yeah, we're certainly
trying to draw from that. And then we're
also looking for opportunities to work
with other jurisdictions. Um I've
suggested having the ability to do ex
run experiments crossborder. So um that
might enable
companies to try things in different
jurisdictions that will provide more
feedback to us as regulators. So I think
there's a lot that can be done. We have
to continue to cooperate. We work
together bilaterally with with
jurisdictions but also through
multilateral organizations. Um I think
some of that work can be positive, some
can be negative. When you put a bunch of
regulators together in a room, what do
they come out with? Hyper regulatory
solutions. So I think we have to take
some of it with a grain of salt.
>> What happens when three SEC regulators
walk into a bar?
>> Exactly.
>> That should be the opening of a new
joke. Thank you very much, Commissioner
Pur. It was an honor meeting you person.
Thank you.